Guide to The Papers of Dorothy and Howard Baker, 1926-1990
Department of Special Collections
The papers of Dorothy and Howard Baker,
1926-1990
Special Collections M0903
Baker, Howard, d1905-
33 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1996.
Scope and Content
Includes manuscripts, correspondence, photographs.
Access Terms
Baker, Dorothy, 1907-1968.; Baker, Howard, 1905-; American literature--20th century.
Container List
Preliminary box listing only
- (HB) Autobiography, temples, horses, his own early papers Stavely, "Individualism" and Wasteland, Shaman, Plates, leather notebook, (red) campus notes notebook, black 3 ring: Temples, black 3 ring: Provinces, general correspondence #9, #10, #11 (Box 1)
- (DB & HB) Whittier H S docs and "iana", UCLA papers and docs, UC-B grad school papers, stories: Safe conduct, vote for Hoover, Matter of habit, No sale, Fletcher Mills, Sane Fourth, For your convenience, Nocturnal conversation; beginnings of "Young man with a horn," family and personal honeymoon pics/doc/yearbooks, HB's letters to his parents (& DB), periodical appearances of DB (Box 2)
- HB: essays, stories, to Virginia: loves of Andy & Rosy, scholarship (Box 3)
- DB: get well, 1947, Trio, Ninth Day, Life with Father, Stories (10)+1, Gifted son clippings, letters to: supplements: Freidel, O'Hare, Murdock, Cassandra (major file) (Box 3)
- Scholarship, 11 folders, Endoxus, etc. (Box 4)
- HB & DB: Little Orpheus (version), The other one (versions), The ninth day (versions of play /screenplay), Orange Valley (setting TS), Ode to the Sea (galleys), HB's poetry (6 folders), Stories: Bedwell Bar, Tokaywabbie special. (Box 5)
- HB: Scholarship & essays: Persephone's cave, Letters on the English, Essays on novels (Hardy et al), Monterey: Acorn gathereres, Folders/Binders on scholarship not valued, Med Fly invention, Essays on Squires, Goldstein, K.A. Porter, etc, box of old snaps/photos some deteriorating. (Box 6)
- Trio (versions) (play), Young man with a horn (versions) (play & screenplay), Willow Street chronicle (play), Sparrow and the characters (play) (Box 7)
- HB: English 262, English 114A: 44B, Hardy, Williams (Annie L), Sullivan - agents, musical rummy, General Lightfoot, Trio 1945, A map in the sand, The Shrew, AVIS (150p jumbled), AVIS & ms map, Antiquity & modernism, Ode to sea (page proofs), A letter from the country TS, English 225 etc (1929), general correspondence #7, #8 (Box 8)
- Supplement box 1/3. DB's letters to parents, early + final roundup + early mss, Bronson endorsement, 1937, for H.M. fellowship, etc. Not foldered, need rubber bands removed. (Box 9)
- HB: Life adv. Of Vicente Felix, AVIS, letters to parents from France, Fed 1040 (1942), Cassandra, The lonely summer, DB's death (medical file) (Box 10)
- DB (chiefly): Orange Valley contract/royalty, DB bio/specs, Nial/Cowley, DB to parents, DB's parents to Alice, 9th Day clipping file, many DB stories, essay (Reluc Provias?), speech, YMWAH (play) drafts & UK stencil, YMWAH play/screenplay (2), YMWAH play/act 2 (drafts), YMWAH (play) 125 pp, ditto 127 pp, ditto Act 1, scene 3, Cassandre at the wedding (galleys - 2 sets), radio/tv, Eddie Blatt, Fletcher Markle, McIntosh & Otis, Annie Laurie Williams, Houghton-Mifflin, clipping service files/YMWAH, Sabinson (Box 11)
- HB & DB: novel ASIS etc drafts, UC Davis files, Trio novel drafts by DB, etc. (Box 12)
- HB: Dilemma, thesis, misc drafts, Sackville & Norton, D's journal, Our gifted son (responses), oral history DB, A final time jazz memoirs, 2nd annual fiction conv., Ellen's birth, Stewart, Mildred (fol. 7), general correspondence #6 (DB) (Box 13)
- HB: manuscript file, Persephone's cave (box 2) (Box 14)
- Specific correspondence: A - Lytle (Box 15)
- Letters to DB: HB, Mildred Stewart, Marjory Harris Simpson, Eliz Freidel, Louise Stoll, French docs (marriage cert.), HB on Dannenbaum, A letter from the country & baby pic, letters from D's parents, Dorothy to Howard (Box 16)
- HB: manuscript file, Persephone's cave (box 1 of 2) (Box 17)
- Specific correspondence (box 2): McCambridge to Wright (to end) + Stewart, Baker, Sullivan, 1970-1971 (important file) (Box 18)
- Supplement box 3/3. Printed matter, galleys, page proofs, Ninth day early drafts, + other mss (Box 19)
- DB: letters to (etc)/general correspondence (5 folders) (Box 20a)
- HB: letters to/general correspondence (6 folders) (Box 20b)
- HB: on Ramsey, French ed YMWAH (A of 4), Whittier HS year books (2), Gyroscope complete with Lesis & Winters TS, HB lc recordings, Cassandra galleys, Hearst/Cosmopolitan, Harvard Advocates (3), DB correspondence (retained carbons, drafts), final folder all scraps (Box 21)
- HB: Supplement box 2/3. Early letters to Dorothy (rubber bands), photos, etc. (Box 22)